draft2digital.com 2019-04-23

# Draft2Digital | Privacy Policy

Last Modified: May 24, 2018

This Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how Draft2Digitial, L.L.C. (“D2D,” “we,” “us,” or “our”), collects, uses and safeguards the personal information we collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the website www.draft2digital.com  (our “Site”), and to assist you in making informed decisions when visiting or purchasing products and/or services through the “Site,” which is owned and operated by Draft2Digitial, L.L.C. 

By using the Site, you consent to our collection and use of the information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to all of the terms of this Privacy Policy, you should proceed no further and obtain no products or services through the Site. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Your continued use of this Site after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the Privacy Policy periodically for updates. 

Unless we state otherwise, this Privacy Policy governs our use of information you provide to us when you call us, write to us, or communicate with us in any manner other than through the Site. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected by us offline or information collected by any third party, including through any application or content (including advertising) that may link to or be accessible from (or on) the Site. 

We use cookies and similar technologies (for example, web beacons, pixels, tags and device identifiers) to recognize you and/or your device(s) on, off, and across the Site and devices. We also log usage data when you use the Site, including when you view or click on content, browser type, browser language, perform a search or request, the date and time of your request, install an update, seek new functionality, or use one or more tools offered through the Site. 

Cookies are pieces of information that websites transfer to your computer's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies will be used if and in the event you make purchases using the Site and we may otherwise use cookies to make visiting our Site easier. Cookies allow us to save preferences for you so that you won’t have to re-enter them the next time you visit. Cookies help us to collect anonymous click-stream data for tracking user trends and patterns. 

Cookies and similar technologies help to facilitate the best possible user experience of the Site as they allow us to recognize you and maintain your user preferences from session to session and help us keep your account safe.  They also help us ensure that your information is used in association with your account. Importantly, we do not use cookies or similar technologies to facilitate interest-based ads from third parties. 

Although most internet browsers accept cookies and the like by default, you can control these types of technology through your browser settings and similar tools and agree to refuse all cookies altogether. If you refuse to accept cookies and similar technologies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser or smartphone, you may prohibit us from delivering the full capability of the Site and preventing the use of certain features and services that require these technologies. 

By agreeing to our Privacy Policy, you agree to the use of cookies and similar technologies as described in this policy.  If you use the Site without changing your browser or device settings to disable cookies, we'll assume that you consent to receive all cookies provided through the Site. 

When you access or leave the Site, we receive the URL of both the site you came from and the one you go to next. We also get information about your IP address, proxy server, operating system, web browser and add-ons, device identifier and features, and/or ISP or your mobile carrier. If you use the Site from a mobile device, that device will send us data about your device based on your phone settings and access you have granted the Site. 

We use this information to prevent fraud and unauthorized access to Site accounts. We also use this information to prevent individuals who have been banned from using our Site due to a violation of this Policy or our Terms from creating new accounts. This information is also used to track total usage and analyze usage data to improve Site functionality. 

We do not share any of your personally identifiable information along with your device identification or location without your explicit permission.  As discussed above, however, we may collect information about your computer and mobile device and internet connection, including the mobile device’s unique device identifier, IP address, operating system, browser type, and mobile network information. If you do not want us to collect this information you should cease use of the Site. 

**What we collect and why.** In order to create an account for the Site, we may collect personally identifiable information of our users, such as name, mailing address, tax ID, email address, and, depending on the payment method you select, payment information such as bank accounts and routing numbers. We may also collect information regarding specific use of the Site by users, such as the dates and times specific content found on the Site is accessed, as well as sales information of books and other publications distributed via our Site and services. We may also use personally-identifiable information you provide to us for purposes of administering our “Refer-A-Friend” Affiliate Program. We do not require that users provide nor do we seek to collect sensitive data such as religious beliefs, race, ethnicity, philosophical beliefs, or physical or mental health to use the Site. 

When you call or email our customer support about a product, delivery, a billing question or for customer service, you may be asked for information that identifies you along with additional information we need to help us promptly answer your questions, such as your name, email information, mailing address and a telephone number where we might contact you. We may retain this information to assist you in the future or as set forth below. 

We may use your information to contact you about account, security, legal and other service-related issues such as the distribution of your publications through the Site or our services, your use of the Site and/or our services, and/or your Site account information. We will do this through in-app messages, push notifications and/or email. Please be aware that you cannot opt-out of receiving service messages from us, including security and legal notices. 

Your personal information is also used in several other ways, now or in the future, to gain a better understanding of our users and their usage pattern, for Site administration and troubleshooting, to create reports, process e-commerce transactions, to create internal reports, to communicate changes and improvements to our website or any registration you have made, improving and analyzing the Site, and to ensure compliance with this Policy and our Terms of Use. 

**What we disclose and why.** We will not intentionally sell, rent, share or otherwise disclose any information provided by you or obtained through your use of the Site to any third party for the purpose of allowing them to market their products or services to you. We may disclose your information to companies that provide support services to us such as printers or mailing houses that help us market our products or services, or web hosts or designers who help us create and maintain this Site. We may disclose your personal information to any of our affiliated entities, including parents, subsidiaries, successors, legal assigns, franchisees, or in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, bankruptcy or reorganization, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company. 

Our strategic partners, vendors, or other service providers may need access to some of your personal information. In such cases, we only provide third party agents with the minimum amount of information needed to complete the requested service or transaction. When you purchase a service from our Site, you authorize D2D to share information with its strategic partners, vendors, or other service providers who are working on our behalf and need access to your information to carry out their work for us so that we may process and deliver to you the purchased service. For example, we may provide limited personal information to our vendors regarding pertaining to publications for the purpose of distributing the same such as an author and/or contributor’s name. We may also make certain personal information available to our vendors and governmental agencies for purposes of processing payments and complying with tax obligations. 

Information shared with such third parties is done securely and these third parties will have access to your information only as reasonably necessary to perform tasks on our behalf to provide you services through the Site and are obligated not to disclose or use it for other purposes. 

Non-personally identifiable user information (such as usage pattern, browser type and your computer) may be shared with third party businesses or advertisers with which we have a business or contractual relationship. We reserve the right to provide third parties with aggregate statistics about our clients, traffic patterns and related site information. This data reflects site usage patterns, but does not contain personally identifiable information about any individual user. Our vendors may provide us with sales information regarding publications distributed through our Site and services. Such information may indicate an author or contributor’s name for an individual publication, but does not include personal information such as tax ID, banking information, etc., and we may share such information with third party businesses or advertisers with which we have a business or contractual relationship. By using our Site and services, you agree to such disclosure. 

We also reserve the right to disclose your personal information: (a) in response to requests from local, state or federal law enforcement officials; (b) in response to any judicial, administrative, or similar proceeding such as a subpoena; (c) when required by law; or (d) in special circumstances such as in response to a physical threat or perceived physical threat to any individual or to enforce the terms of use of this Site. 

Please keep in mind that if you disclose personally identifiable information in a public manner whether through collaborative postings, message boards or other public on-line forums, this information may be collected and used by others. We do not monitor or collect information you disclose inside online public forums nor do we accept any liability associated with your voluntary disclosure of same. 

Please also keep in mind that the Site may contain links to other websites. You are responsible for reviewing the privacy statements and policies of those other websites you choose to link to or from the Site, so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and store your information. We are not responsible for the privacy statements, policies or content of other websites, including websites you link to or from our Site. Websites containing co-branding (referencing our name and a third party’s name) contain content delivered by the third party and not us. 

We have implemented industry standard encryption and security solutions to protect our servers against intrusion. Access to our servers and users’ personal information by D2D employees is limited to a need-to-know basis. Sensitive information related to payment such as tax IDs and banking information is encrypted and stored on a separate server with no direct write-access. When you place orders on our site, your order information, including your card number and delivery address, is transmitted through the internet using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. SSL technology works with your browser to encrypt your order information before transmitting it to our processing facility. 

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone. 

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our Site. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Site. 

Visitors to our Site may be given the opportunity to choose whether to have their information used for certain purposes at the point where we ask for the information. Visitors and users of the Site may also be sent messages concerning selected products, companies and/or events that we think may interest you. If you later decide you do not want to be contacted for such promotional purposes, please let us know through the opt-out procedures described in those communications or contact as at the contact information found at www.draft2digital.com/contact/ or by emailing us at [support@draft2digital.com](mailto:support@draft2digital.com). 

For personal data that we have about you, you have the following rights: 

  * **Deletion** : You may ask us to erase or delete all or some of your personal data. Please note that doing so may limit your ability to use certain functionality of the Site. Please note that your name and an email address is required to have a membership account. 
  * **Correction/Modification** : You may edit some of your personal data through your account or ask us to change, update, or fix your data in certain cases, including if it’s inaccurate. 
  * **Object to, or Limit or Restrict, Use of Data** : You can ask us to stop using all or some of your personal data (for example, if we have no legal right to keep using it) or to limit our use of it (for example, if your personal data is inaccurate or unlawfully held). 
  * **Right to Access and/or Take Your Data** : You can ask us for a copy of your personal data you provided to us. 

To make these or any other requests with respect to your personal information, please send an e-mail to  [support@draft2digital.com](mailto:support@draft2digital.com) or write to us at Draft2Digitial, LLC; Attn: Customer Service, 9400 N. Broadway, Ste. 410, Oklahoma City, OK 73114 

We ask that individuals making requests identify themselves and identify the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before we process any requests. We may decline to process requests if we cannot verify the requestor's identity, if we believe the request will jeopardize the privacy of others, if we believe the change would violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect, or for a similar legitimate purpose. In any case, where we provide information access, deletion or correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. 

If you choose to close your account or ask that we modify or delete some or all of your personal information, we will retain your personal data if reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations (including law enforcement requests), meet regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, maintain security, prevent fraud and abuse, enforce our Terms of Use or fulfill any others requests from you (for example, to opt-out of further messages or for a copy of your data) 

We have no control of information you have shared with others through the Site after you close your account or asked to delete information or attempted to delete your account yourself. Your information and content you have shared may continue to be displayed in the services of others (for example, search engine results) until they refresh their cache. 

We may include links to the websites of our business partners, vendors, social media websites, and advertisers. The inclusion of any link does not imply our endorsement of any other company, its websites, or its products and/or services. These linked websites have separate and independent privacy policies, which we encourage you to read carefully. We have no control over such websites and therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content on such sites or the manner in which the organizations that operate such linked websites may collect, use, disclose or otherwise treat your personal information. If you decide to access any of the third-party websites linked to this Site, you do so entirely at your own risk and subject to the terms and conditions of use for such websites. This Privacy Policy only applies to the current Site and information collected on this Site. 

California Civil Code Section § 1798.83 permits users of our Site that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to  [support@draft2digital.com](mailto:support@draft2digital.com) or write to us at Draft2Digitial, LLC; Attn: Customer Service, 9400 N. Broadway, Ste. 410, Oklahoma City, OK 73114 

If you believe that any content appearing on the site has been copied in a way that constitutes copyright infringement please forward the following information to the address below: 

  * Your name, address, telephone number, and email address;
  * A description of the copyrighted work that you claim has been infringed;
  * The exact URL or a description of where the alleged infringing material is located;
  * A statement by you that you have a good faith belief that the disputed use is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; 
  * An electronic or physical signature of the person authorized to act on behalf of the owner of the copyright interest; and 
  * A statement by you, made under penalty of perjury, that the above information in your notice is accurate and that you are the copyright owner or authorized to act on the copyright owner’s behalf. 

Draft2Digitial, LLC; Attn: Customer Service, 9400 N. Broadway, Ste. 410, Oklahoma City, OK 73114 

Please note that while D2D seeks to preserve any and all exemptions from liability that may be available under applicable law, this is not a stipulation that D2D is subject to the United States Digital Millennium Copyright Act, or similar laws of other jurisdictions, or that D2D is a “service provider” as defined by such acts or elsewhere in the law. 

You agree to defend, indemnify, and hold D2D together with its affiliates, officers, directors, employees, agents, licensors, and suppliers, harmless from and against any claims, actions or demands, damages, liabilities and settlements including without limitation, reasonable legal and accounting fees, resulting from, or alleged to result from, your violation of our Terms of Use for the Site or this Privacy Policy. 

We will only collect and process personal data about you where we have lawful bases. Lawful bases include consent (where you have given consent), contract (where processing is necessary for the performance of a contract with you (such as providing the Site and functionality you request and acting in accordance with this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use) and other legitimate interests.   Such legitimate interest include protection to you, us and other Site users and third parties, to comply with applicable law, to enable and administer our business, to manage corporate transactions, to generally understand and improve our business and user relationships, and to enable us and other users of the Site to connect with you to exchange information, provided that the foregoing adequately protects your rights and freedoms. 

Where we rely on your consent to process personal data, you have the right to withdraw or decline your consent at any time and where we rely on legitimate interests, you have the right to object. If you have any questions about the lawful bases upon which we collect and use your personal data, please contact us at [support@draft2digital.com](mailto:support@draft2digital.com) or write to us at Draft2Digitial, LLC; Attn: Customer Service, 9400 N. Broadway, Ste. 410, Oklahoma City, OK 73114 

The Site is offered in and from Oklahoma within the United States and your use of the Site and this Privacy Policy is governed by the laws of the United States and the State of Oklahoma.   If you are using the Site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where the servers that host the Site are located and our central database is operated. We process data both inside and outside of the United States and rely on legally-provided mechanisms to lawfully transfer data across borders. This includes contractual commitments between us and companies transferring personal data that require the protection and security of such data. Nevertheless, the data protection and other laws of the State of Oklahoma, the United States, and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country.  By using the Site, you consent to your information being transferred to our facilities and to the facilities of those third-parties with whom we share it with as described in this Privacy Policy. 

You may modify the personal information you provide us. We may modify this Privacy Policy at any time and will indicate when changes have been made by revising the date at the top of this Privacy Policy. If we make material changes to how we treat our users’ personal information, we will notify you by e-mail to the email address you provide to us or through a notice of the home page of our Site. The date the Privacy Policy was last revised is identified at the top of the page. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date active and deliverable e-mail address for you, and for periodically visiting our Site and this privacy policy to check for any changes. Your continued usage of the Site following the posting of such changes shall mean you accept and consent to those changes. You can print the version of the Privacy Policy that you reviewed and compare it to the version in effect when you use our Site in the future to determine what, if any, changes have been made. 

We cannot completely ensure the privacy of your electronic communications with us. These communications could be intercepted without your or our knowledge and permission, while in transit to or from our Site. If you are concerned about your privacy, we suggest that you do not use electronic methods of communication to provide information to us that you consider sensitive information. 

By using the Site you agree that we are not responsible or liable to you for (i) any disclosure of your personal information made by you to a third party through your use of the Site; (ii) any disclosure of your personal information obtained illegally from us; or (iii) any accidental disclosure of your personal information made by us. 

We do not collect or maintain information from anyone known to be under the age of 18, and no part of this website is designed to attract anyone under the age of 18. We do not sell products or services intended for purchase by minors or children. If you are under 18, you may only use the Site under the supervision of a parent or guardian. If we discover or are otherwise notified that we have received any such information from a minor in violation of this policy, we will delete that information. 

The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) protects the online privacy and personal information of children under 13 years of age. No one under the age of 13 may provide any personally identifiable information to the Site. D2D does not intentionally collect any personally identifiable information from children under 13. If we learn we have collected or received personal information from a child under 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at the address, email, or phone number listed above. 

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us at the contact information referenced above. 

D2D welcomes your feedback and comments regarding this Site and its existing products and marketing practices; however, please note that D2D does not accept or consider unsolicited ideas in any form (aside from the publications we distribute through the Site), including ideas for new concepts, advertising campaigns, new promotions, artwork, or new or improved products or technology. D2D is happy to receive your feedback; however, please do not send any unsolicited ideas so that we may avoid any misunderstandings or disputes should D2D independently develop or already have developed a concept, product, technology, or other project that may be similar or even identical to the unsolicited idea. If despite our request that you not send us any unsolicited ideas, you still submit them, then you agree that: (1) your idea will immediately upon submission become the sole and exclusive property of D2D without any compensation to you; (2) there is no obligation for D2D to review the submission; (3) D2D will consider the submission to be non-confidential and non-proprietary and there is no obligation for D2D to keep any submission confidential; and (4) D2D shall be entitled to unrestricted use of the submission for any purpose and in any way. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not submit an unsolicited idea to us. 

Any rights not expressly granted herein are reserved. 

Copyright Notice: 2018 Draft2Digital, L.L.C. All Rights Reserved. 

Trademarks: Draft2Digital, D2D, and logos are either registered trademarks or trademarks of Draft2Digital, L.L.C. in the U.S. and/or other countries. The names of other entities, products or services mentioned herein or on the Site may be the trademarks of their respective owners. 

Thank you for visiting us at www.draft2digital.com.
